[{"question":"Vitamin By is related with:","a":"FAD","b":"NAD","c":"NADP","d":"CoA","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The centre of hunger or centre which regulates the amount of food we eat or our appetite is located in:","a":"Medulla","b":"Cerebrum","c":"Hypothalamus","d":"Alimentary canal","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which of the following is a freely movable muscular organ that is attached to the floor of the oral cavity by the frenulum?","a":"Jaws","b":"Teeth","c":"Tongue","d":"Salivary glands","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The lymph vessels called lacteals, are found in:","a":"Mammary glands","b":"Pancreas","c":"Mucosa of intestine","d":"Villi of ileum","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Pylorus occurs between:","a":"Ileum and rectum","b":"Duodenum and ileum","c":"Stomach and duodenum","d":"Oesophagus and stomach","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The innermost layer of the digestive tract is the:","a":"Serosa membrane","b":"Mucosa membrane","c":"Submucosa membrane","d":"Lumen","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The sphincter of Oddi is present between:","a":"Oesophagus and cardiac stomach.","b":"Pyloric stomach and duodenum.","c":"Hepatic duct and cystic duct.","d":"Hepatopancreatic duct and duodenum.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Parotid salivary glands are present:","a":"Below the tongue","b":"Below the ears","c":"In the angle between two jaws","d":"Below the eye orbits","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The common bile duct in human is formed by the joining of","a":"Pancreatic duct and bile duct","b":"Cystic duct and hepatic duct","c":"Cystic duct and pancreatic duct","d":"Hepatic duct and pancreatic duct","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which of the following is the correct chronological order for flow of food from mouth to anus?","a":"Oesophagus Stomach→→ Small intestine →→ Large Intestine","b":"Large intestine → Oesophagus→ Stomach →→ Small Intestine","c":"Small intestine→→ Large intestine →→ Oesophagus Stomach","d":"Stomach Small intestine→ Large intestine Oesophagus","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"If the epiglottis does not function correctly, then what will happen to the human being?","a":"One might congest.","b":"Peristalsis will discontinue.","c":"Acid reflux disease will damage the oesophagus.","d":"Swallowing will be difficult or impossible.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"The enormously long tusks in elephant are:","a":"Upper incisors","b":"Upper canines","c":"Lower canines","d":"Lower incisors","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following type of enzyme is not matched correctly with the molecule that it breaks down?","a":"Amylase-Starch","b":"Lipase-Starch","c":"Protease-Proteins","d":"Disaccharidase-Sugars","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Vitamin needed for blood coagulation is:","a":"E","b":"D","c":"K","d":"C","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Cod liver oil is a good source of:","a":"Vitamin B","b":"Vitamin C","c":"Vitamin A","d":"lodine","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"How does a gastrovascular cavity differ from an alimentary canal? The gastrovascular cavity","a":"stores food but does not digest it.","b":"is usually much larger.","c":"has only one opening.","d":"functions in digestion but not absorption.","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"True stomach in cud-chewing animals is:","a":"Abomasum","b":"Reticulum","c":"Omasum","d":"Rumen","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following vitamin is essential for normal vision?","a":"Folic acid","b":"Biotin","c":"Riboflavin","d":"Niacin","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Which one is essential for DNA replication or  cell division?","a":"Vit. E","b":"Folic acid","c":"Vit. K","d":"Vit. D","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Intestinal villi are more numerous and larger in posterior part of small intestine than in anterior  part because:","a":"digestion is faster in posterior part.","b":"blood supply is poorer in anterior part.","c":"blood supply is poorer in posterior part.","d":"there is more of digested food in posterior part.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"How would you expect the digestive system of a hawk, a carnivore, to be compared with that of a sparrow, a seed-eater?","a":"The hawk would have a larger gastrovascular cavity.","b":"The sparrow's digestive system would be longer.","c":"The hawk would have a gizzard, but the sparrow would not.","d":"How would you expect the digestive system of a hawk, a carnivore, to be compared with that of a sparrow, a seed-eater?","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Liver cells secrete:","a":"Amylopsin","b":"Trypsin","c":"Bile and no enzymes","d":"Lipase","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Physiologically, vitamin E is known To be ","a":"Anti-inflammatory","b":"A powerful antioxidant","c":"An important co-enzyme","d":"Anti-hypertensive factor","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Which is the best source for vitamin B","a":"Cod liver oil","b":"Egg","c":"Whole wheat bread","d":"Card","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Vitamin By is related with:","a":"FAD","b":"NAD","c":"NADP","d":"CoA","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Phyalin cannot work in stomach, because it is:","a":"inactivated by pepsin.","b":"inactivated by HCI.","c":"carbohydrate-digesting enzyme.","d":"inactivated by runnin.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"The structure which prevents entry of food into windpipe during swallowing in mammals is","a":"Larynx","b":"Pharynx","c":"Glottis","d":"Epiglottis","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"The deficiency of which vitamin is known to cause abortion in carly pregnancy of rat?","a":"Retinol","b":"Calciferol","c":"Tocopherol","d":"Napthoquinone","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"The swallowing of food from buccal cavity into oesophagus is a reflex action controlled by:","a":"Brain","b":"Medulla oblongata","c":"Hormones","d":"Peripheral nerves","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Digestion of proteins, fats and carbohydrate is completed in:","a":"Stomach","b":"Duodenum","c":"lleum","d":"None of these","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Glottis is a structure which","a":"prevents entry of food into windpipe during swallowing food.","b":"allows food to pass into oesophagus.","c":"produces sound as air is forced through it","d":"allows air to enter in trachea.","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Succus entericus is secreted by:","a":"Villi of intestine","b":"Drummer's glands","c":"Crypts of Lieberkuhn","d":"Brunner's glands and Crypts of Licberkuhn","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Hydrolysis of phospholipids yield","a":"Glycerol, phosphoric acid and fatty acids","b":"Glycerol, phosphoric acid and nitrogen base","c":"Glycerol & fatty acids.","d":"Acetyl.coA.","hint":"","correct":"a"},{"question":"Which of the following food reserves would be first used in a starving person?","a":"Muscle proteins","b":"Skin adipose tissue","c":"Liver glycogen","d":"Liver proteins","hint":"","correct":"c"},{"question":"Secretion of hormone cholecystokinin is for:","a":"Controlling blood pressure","b":"Absorption of iron","c":"Release of insulin","d":"Bile functions","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Trypsinogen is produced by:","a":"Liver","b":"Duodenum","c":"Stomach","d":"Pancreas","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"When gall bladder of a man is removed:","a":"fat digestion is not possible.","b":"acidity continues in duodenum.","c":"effect of pancreatic juice upon food is impaired.","d":"All of the above","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"Contraction of gall bladder is induced by:","a":"Gastrin","b":"Cholecystokinin","c":"Secretin","d":"Enterogastrone","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"Meals which are rich in fat are not digested in the intestine in absence of:","a":"Pepsin","b":"Enterokinase","c":"Insulin","d":"Steapsin","hint":"","correct":"d"},{"question":"When a piece of bread is chewed, it tastes sweet because:","a":"the sugar contents are drawn out.","b":"saliva converts starch into maltose.","c":"it does not taste sweet.","d":"the taste buds are stimulated by chewing.","hint":"","correct":"b"},{"question":"When a piece of bread is chewed, it tastes sweet because:","a":"the sugar contents are drawn out.","b":"saliva converts starch into maltose.","c":"it does not taste sweet.","d":"the taste buds are stimulated by chewing.","hint":"","correct":"b"}]